I'll just cut to the chase. Owning a
home is a horrible, horrible, horrible
investment. It's a liability. The house
could triple. You never hear the white
going, "Let's sell it, make our 300%."
That never It's not an investment. It
should be illegal to say a home is an
investment. People do not need cash.
Everybody should wish for inflation.
Everybody should want inflation.
Inflation is a great great thing. When
you come into this casino, they take
your cash, convert it to a chip with
their name name on it. It's no longer
your chip. And the guy spends 2 hours
losing his money when the truth is he
lost it when he walked in. Growing up
like that, would you say you are you
were insecure when it comes to money?
Oh, 1,000%. When Sailor saw my fund,
he's like, "That's a fund." I
don't know how you say that in
Taiwanese, but
I don't think we're going to have a
recession. I don't think we're going to
have a depression. These are made up
numbers. We should have had 14
recession. We have had we we we were
rolling administration was no one's
admitting it. They don't they have
redefined GDP, CPI. Oh gosh, we just
declared war against Ukraine. Nothing
moves, man. And and the VIX goes down
and the S&P goes up. You're like, "Hey,
this is rigged." None of these numbers
make sense. I think most people are good
people, but when they get scared and
they see no possible way to win. They do
things that are bad. We've added 40% of
all the paper in the United States was
bad in the last 5 years. A lot of money.
Take your emergency account, keep it at
zero all the time. Take that emergency
money and make sure you're investing in
something where you know you can't lose.
And when the emergency comes, do not
fund it out of the thing you invested
in. Fund it. I don't want liquidity cuz
I do I do dumb stuff. But if we're not
liquid, how do I buy it? Yeah, I I I
have a very different answer. This is
where it gets crazy. The conversation
gets nutso right now.
What a treat to have both the Cardones
with us, Gary and Grant. Well, Grant and
Gary, I think I was thinking I was
looking at I was looking at you. My mind
meant the other way, but Bonnie Chang is
my co-host, and we're just super excited
to have you both. You've got fans all
over the world, right?
Um,
we're going to get to your Bitcoin
outlook. We're going to talk about
business. We're going to talk about
life. a lot of things. Bonnie, why don't
you start? How would you describe each
other? Oh, dude, that's a great
question, Bonnie. That is a good
question. Um, my brother's extremely
intelligent. Um, very uh nimble. Uh,
very difficult to pin down. Like, you
can try to pin him down, he's coming
back. Um, very extremely resilient, a
lot of courage. Uh, and extremely great
at relationships, very long-term
relationship builder. um and and
extremely caring
uh sharing and loves people. That's how
I would describe him. Wow, that's a lot.
I'm not sure I have that much for you.
One, you're brilliant. Okay, that just
articulated the brilliance. Um look,
he's a force of nature, right? Once he
decides to do something, it's uh you
would not want to bet against him. So,
powerhouse, that's the way I put it.
You both grew up middle class kids from
Louisiana. You both took very It feel
like middle class. I didn't know what it
felt like really. It was middle classy.
We were told over and over it was the
middle class. But you had very different
life paths, but you both ended up super
successful twins. Statistically
improbable,
but it happened. Yeah. Walk us through
how that happened. That's a good
question, man. You guys ask a good
question. So, I don't know how it
happened. uh you know we were both bad
students we were you know right I don't
know that I was a bad student I think I
was a very uh uh bored I was bored and
the teachers were boring and the subject
was boring
the whole construct was boring actually
I felt prison I just remember my dad
died when we were 10 and the money
stopped right like you we didn't know
money stopped at 10 years old you don't
know anything happen. You're not looking
at the checking accounts, but you could
feel when my mom should have been
experiencing grief. She was in fear. I
think the house was sold the next week.
The the house my dad had spent his whole
life preparing to buy.
He he was debtree, had some life
insurance. I think they had some stocks
like some AT&T dividend stocks that paid
every quarter. All this would have a lot
to do with who I would become later
because I'm like, "Okay, the quarterly
dividend doesn't work because my mom was
in fear every two and three months."
And the house didn't work because she
had to sell it. Um, whatever cash they
had, she was just basically having to
manage it. You're not creating when
you're managing. So, I was learning all
these lessons at 10 and 12 and 13 and 14
years old. I didn't even know I was
learning these these lessons. Uh, so uh
saving money didn't work. She she's the
one that pushed the college thing. You
guys should go to college. College was a
complete waste of time for both of us. I
I'm I'm speaking for him, but it was
definitely a waste of time for me. Every
bad habit I have was learned in high
school and college. And um so, you know,
that's look and I when I look back
today, I'm like many of the things that
happened to me in those very critical
years is why I invest the way I do
today. Gary. Well, it's interesting to
hear, Grants. Um because I I I don't
have that. That's not my memory. I do
remember my mom being really terrified,
but I I think um there's something I I
suspect there's something one losing the
dad, but also he and I's u like we have
this thing that like if he starts
cutting up here, I will most certainly
start cutting up and then he will want
to cut up to another like we'll just
spin each other up. This is why we live
in different cities, states, and
sometimes countries. But like I just
needed to get out of the house, man. I
was lost at 20 years old. I had no idea.
Did you feel like you were your biggest
competitors? No. No. We we weren't like
it was very clear to me we were going in
totally different directions. So as soon
as I got out of college with economics
and marketing background, I left. I mean
I went to Houston and I didn't come
back. Yeah. And I went corporate. Now
the story I would share for the audience
is he went highly independent. I'm never
going to work for anyone. Um, and I
went, hey, I'm not smart enough to be my
own guy in the business. I'm I was going
into oil and gas. I can't do that by
myself. So, I spent 17 years working for
a company and did pretty well. So, you
know, for me, the message is, oh wow,
guy goes all by himself, does really
well. Guy goes into corporate, does
really well. What's the similarities?
Extreme focus. Once we found our little
window, the the focus was pretty
unparalleled. And and speaking of the
window, I think the middle class really
like if you if you grow up like we were
really poor. We we weren't I mean not
really poor but we weren't middle
whatever that means like it's your
question. What is it like it's it's just
a it's a place to call not poor because
basically your one emergency, one credit
card, one mistake,
just one investment from being a poor
person. One job out of being poor. My my
dad died. It wasn't his fault. his heart
explodes and the next thing you know my
mom's having to sell the house. So that
house is not an asset at that moment.
It's a liability and the the ability no
money coming in was like, "Oh no
money comes in. You got to change
everything." She did not know how to get
money. And and I'm I'm watching this, I
look back now and I'm like, "Oh, my dad
was a great people person. My mom
wasn't. She was not good at going out
and meet people." My dad could meet
anybody and that's why he got money. So
I'm like, "Oh, that's the trick. The
hack is people. My brother's great at
people." You know, I've learned how to
use social media and people. People
means money. There's no shortage of
money. There's a shortage of people
contacting other people. So, um, and my
dad knew how to play that game, but
nobody was there to teach us. So, here I
am, 15, man. I'm like, got three uncles.
He can't teach him anything.
We We don't It's the blind leading the
blind, right? So, teach you how to go
hospital. Yeah. Yeah. But, but so, you
know, I'm like, "Okay, I got one of
three uncles. I know one of these guys
going to show up." I wasn't expecting my
mom to teach us. I'm like, there's got
to be a man that's gonna step in and
help us. And they did. And they had
their families. And so, I'm 15 years
old. I'm like, I told my mom one day, I
said, I'm gonna get rich. I'm going to
get so rich. I will never worry about
money again. When When hell were you
when 15 years old? I remember it like it
was yesterday. I said, cuz she's
clipping coupons. My mom knew where to
save everything. She know where to get
gas, where not to, where to go get
blueberries, what day. Like, this was
all calculation. She was a genius at it.
Mhm. And this this this this prevented
me from having extreme wealth much for
many most of my life. He was around the
corporations. So he saw these guys
spending making hundreds of billions of
dollars investments. I'm selling cars at
28 years old. I'm hustling $200
commissions. So complete different
upbringings, right? And the way we do
money now is completely not different
upbringings but
different different experiences with the
professional life. Yeah. Upbringing,
right? Coming out of being a kid. And so
I'm hustling $200 commissions,
working, you know, 14-hour days. He's
around companies that are talking about
oil and gas investments that are
hundreds of millions of dollars. And
he's seeing the world, and I didn't do
that. So our our view of the world and
money is is very different because of
those experiences.
Um growing up like that would you say
you are you were insecure when it comes
to money? Oh 1,000%. And that didn't
help you or did it? Did it help me?
Yeah. No. No. I I I was like very
insecure about money. How do I get it?
How do I keep it? What do I do with it?
I remember I I was 31 years old and
realized I had a million dollars sitting
in savings accounts. I didn't even know
I had a million dollars. When I saw that
I had a million dollars, I became
terrified. I'm like, "Oh my god, now I
really don't know anything." You know,
so I would say I was extremely insecure
about money.
Do you think you still are? uh to some
degree. Yeah, to some degree I'm still I
still am influenced by a
uh I I lack the capacity to take great
risk. So I I play very everything very
conservative. When when Sailor saw my
fund the second time we went spent with
Mike Sailor, I showed him what we were
going to do with our real estate crypto
uh or real estate Bitcoin hybrid and
he's like, "That's a fund."
I don't know how you say that in
Taiwanese, but
we're going to get to that fun just a
minute, but I want to talk about uh
business and working for yourself. I'll
start with you, Gary, first. Same
question for both of you. At what point
in your life did you have this click aha
moment where you went, I'm not going to
work for anybody else anymore? I I've
never had that. Me either. I've never
had the idea that I would not I I I go
work for you tomorrow morning, Bonnie.
I've had so many terrified I've had so
many people say this. Oh, you will never
work for anyone. I'm like, I gladly work
for anyone if they're nice people and
they have a big idea and I bring value
all day long. You know, I don't have I I
have a a lineage of ideas, but I have a
ve a shortage of teams and armies that I
can go work with that actually can get
something done. Whether that's one
person or five, it's very very hard. So,
I don't think I've ever had that. I did
have
the the the the moment I no longer had a
boss or my bosses were separated by
6,000 miles
and no one stepped over me and they
allowed me to
um stand up to the level of
responsibility that the market offered
me. I I was like, "Wow, I can grow, man,
if someone's not holding me down." and I
needed a lot of help, but I had really
really good instincts and I just needed
to be given responsibility and don't
save me. Please don't save me. Like let
me, you know, work through my issues.
Um, and I I I don't
like I would not want to work alone. And
most people look at me and go, I don't
have any in place, but I do work alone,
but I really work with a lot of people.
Um there's too much information in the
world today not to like plug in. I mean,
I plugged into you what three or four
years ago because I knew, look, you he
he knows something about this part of
the world and I saw what was happening
with data and why wouldn't I want to,
you know, hook up with Yeah. Um, you
know, they're channels, man. There's
there's packages of data. He has
connections. I He has connections. Like,
I think the great mistake he and I make
is we and and many people in the
industries, we don't use our
connections. Well, like he meets people
that are energy people, he should
immediately go, "Hey, Gary, like like
this cat like I know so much about
energy." Um, and it's not so much about
doing a strategic reserve with an energy
player. It's like, "Oh, wow. How much
energy is this guy, you'll understand
this, David, how much storage
or energy players using every year that
they literally would not need to use if
they were mining Bitcoin? storage for
natural gas costs $3 a year. The price
of natural gas is $3.
So it's 100% to store energy and energy
moves like this, right? People are lit
Howard Ham is literally going to look at
it and go, I'm not going to spend a
dollar on a unit of natural gas that
trades for free when I can mine Bitcoin
for a small capital cost and then take
that Bitcoin, put it on my balance sheet
just like the oil and the gas sit on my
balance sheet. It's a commodity and they
under the Fazby rules and they will suck
that up all day long. And who's going to
lose? The storage providers will lose.
Guess what? Their intermediaries.
And Bitcoin, this whole crypto, it's
about shrinking the intermediaries
involved in a really complex analog
value chain that's been created over
150, 200 years. And we never had these
digital tools. on my telephone. I can
literally tell you exactly how small or
large that dimension is that was not
available 3, four years ago. So, it's
really a staggering amount of technology
change and we just like there's so much
going on that I don't think you can do
this alone. I think it's a real it's a
club or team effort
there. There actually I I don't think
there's much competition in this
industry. People should not look at a
zero sum game here. They should look at
I just I own a tax talking about working
together. I own a company that does
really high-end audits for crypto
uh HF high frequency traders and there
was three two or three competitors out
there like tax bit and some other guys
and we were all chatting. I said, "Hey,
why don't we all meet?" You would meet
with us. I said, "Dude, you're not my
competitor. There's eight billion people
on this planet. We can't serve all these
people there. There there's the IRS,
there's the SEC, there's the DA. Every
one of these people are moving into
crypto. They're they're having to look
at the world as we digitize it and there
are no tools. Okay? There are no tool.
There are pencils and there's pieces of
paper just like there was a cave wall
and there was some blood and they did a
paint thing or there was a stone wheel.
You're not going to throw the stone
wheel down the 405 at 3:00 in the
afternoon. It's going to cause it is a
wheel. Yeah. But it ain't going to work
well. And I think that's a really good
analogy where we're headed. The the the
the tools we have are very heavy to move
into a world that's light, right? It's
just data. I'm going to throw a
curveball at you guys. I'll start with
you, Grant. Yeah. What would crash the
markets 50 80% of the next year? If you
had to pinpoint one or two global events
and how would you hedge against that as
an investor? Basically, the biggest
risks facing investors were just world
peace overall.
What would crash the markets? I mean,
look, the only thing I don't know that I
have an answer to that, but the only
thing standing between Donald Trump
having the best economy in the history
of the United States is a 10-year
Treasury. If that comes down, and it
won't it will not come down. Okay. Uh,
he hates this part. He's a real estate
guy. But, but look, Grant, the truth is
four and a half to 5%. You would buy 5%
money for 20 years to be good right now.
You'd rip their faces off and everybody
else would. That's why the 10 years at
that number. Yeah, because the demand's
there. The you and I grew up in an 8 and
a half% marketplace. What's wrong with
five? Doesn't matter. Doesn't matter.
The the cost of assets are so much more
expensive today. No, the cost of the
payment on a single family home is not
affordable. Cost 80% of the people that
are trying to qualify for one. The only
problem is the 2021 vintage of
investments made at Orange. No, that's
not that's not the biggest problem that
blown out and the people are upset. The
biggest problem and they don't want to
take the loss. Sorry. The biggest
problem is the single family homes.
Okay. That 70% of those are sitting on
somewhere between sub4 I think 30% of
them are paid for in cash. Those people
can't trade the housing market and the
mortgage market. So they're locked. The
Fanny Freddy. You're saying they're
locked in. They can't actually move
because the rate is they can't they
can't move. They can't they can't move.
This is a this is a Bitcoin problem.
It's a fiat problem. Yeah. But but
you're not you're not finishing the
first problem. Don't be tight though
because I think it's really important.
Like the fiat problem is a guy has a 4%
interest rate. Rates are eight or seven.
He in order the rates aren't the the
next mortgage is Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Wait,
excuse me. The next his money's earning
a half a percent.
So, so his maybe a quarter of a percent.
So, he's paying he's paying four when
his money earns nothing. Yeah. And the
the the for David to go buy a new house
in Toronto. I mean, you can't even get a
fixed loan there. That what that's why
the single family will crash in Canada.
And it won't crash here because and
we're not answering your question
really, but the single family can't
crash here because you have 70% of these
loans sitting at sub4. So there's no
crash in single family. Now he's talking
about the, you know, 3.7 trillion
sitting in commercial money that's
adjustable and it's maturing right now.
But those guys just keep kicking the
can. It's so big, the problem's so big,
they're just going to keep kicking it.
Uh, what would crash the You're talking
about the Bitcoin market or the stock
market? You're gonna come to an answer.
We're gonna We're gonna kick it around.
No, I'm trying to come to an I just You
can kick it and then come to an answer.
We got We got all day. Bitcoin and stock
markets, they're correlated. But yeah, I
mean public market. It doesn't seem like
any anything can kill either one of
them. Yeah. Which is mindboggling to me.
I would have thought the stock market
would be off many times more than it is
today. I don't understand it. Right. I
mean, the reality is there's 493 of the
S&P 500 stocks. Haven't made anybody any
money in a long time. That's not
advertised by your people. You guys
don't put that message out on a daily
basis. It should. And then what what
brings Bitcoin down? I don't think
anything brings it down. Like I think it
gets crushed one day and then tomorrow
it's going to ride hot.
That's Yeah. Um I watch a lot of your
interviews and there are some very
interesting statement about money that
Grant made and I want to know what Gary
thinks. Uh people should not save.
True. People should invest not save.
Saving. Saving. Save. Like um he he made
a good point one day. People that like I
know somebody that's got $300,000 in
cash waiting for an emergency. Yeah. And
she has more insurance than this entire
convention center. But she's got
insurance. It's our sister. She's got
more damn insurance, health, life,
whatever. And she's got 300 grand for a
emergency. And that's a lot of money for
an emergency. And she's she doesn't
spend more than 100 bucks, 100 bucks a
month. So she's got enough money for
like 35 years. Totally. She's never
needed more than three. And and then the
the inverse is the person, okay, I have
$7,000 that I'm saving for an emergency.
I cannot possib I'm going to save it
under my pillow. Well, that money is not
doing anything. By the way, every
emergency is going to be over seven
grand and they all take you back to
zero. So, that you're better off being
zero and calling your mom up and going.
You're better off going to zero on your
own, not having an emergency take you to
zero. So, let's let's say if your cost
of living was three grand a month and
you're like Dave Ramsey would be like,
you need $9,000. I'm like, Dave, this is
kind of stupid, bro. You're just going
back and forth. You're yo-yo. You're
literally funding an emergency. You're
you're manifesting an emergency with
your money. Now, if I may, you earn
nothing. Hang on a second. You're
earning nothing on it. And then you're
pulling the emergency in. Now, if if if
you can't pull your own emergency in,
guess what? Your father-in-law is going
to pull an emergency in, which is even
worse. He's going to have a damn
emergency and it's going to cost exactly
$9,000. And they're going to come to you
because you have 9,000 in emergency
account. And you're so guilty.
I funded for the emergency so I should
save them. If you didn't have the Z,
what I would say is just take your
emergency account, keep it at zero all
the time, take that emergency money,
make sure you're investing in something
where you know you can't lose. And when
the emergency comes, do not fund it out
of the thing you invested in. Fund it
with people. Go hustle other people.
David, I need nine grand for my
emergency. Can you help me? Remember
that interview I did for you with my
brother? That interview? Okay,
give me nine grand, bro. I'll give it
back to you one day. Did you
The next one is you don't want to be
liquid. I don't want liquidity because I
do I do dumb stuff. But all these all
the you got to admit there's 50% of
these people in this conference are
degenerates. Like you give them
liquidity. They'll buy today, sell
tomorrow, buy today. They're going to
buy at the wrong time, sell at the wrong
time. That's why these casinos do so
well. Okay? When you come into this
casino, they take your cash, convert it
to a chip with their name name on it. It
is no longer your chip. and the guy
spends two hours losing his money when
the truth is he lost it when he walked
in. He locked it when he said, "Here's
$100. Give me a chip." That's when he
lost his money. Liquidity is a problem
for most people.
But if we're not liquid, how do I buy
the dip? Yeah, I I I have a very
different answer. I I don't think
liquidity is a bad thing. I want to be
liquid. I actually want a plan for my
liquidity. I I want to Most people don't
just have stacks of cash sitting on
their bed. Hey, I'm looking to deploy
it. Um, I need I like planning for
liquidity. Now that I understand
Bitcoin, and I think I do really
understand Bitcoin, it allows me to
really fund this investment. Now, what
people are so scared of, they talk about
all that volatility. I look at it and
go, "Oh my god." It allows you to plan
for your seeding, for your investment
into this. And you you most certainly
hope this thing continues through
actually a a transparent cycle of what
the assets worth that other assets don't
actually have. And I think real estate
is an extremely opaque. And I don't care
if it's commercial, residential,
multi-dwelling.
Once a once a sector collapses, it will
suck in the rest of the sector that
there's no Yeah, I agree with that. Oh
gosh, I'm protected because I own a $14
million home. You're going down, too.
Like, so, well, to back to David's
question, nuclear war most certainly
would destroy the economy. Sure. For
sure. Destroy a lot of things. But, but
I don't see that the economy is
destructible. I don't think we're gonna
have a recession. And I don't think
you're going to have a depression. Uh
these are made up numbers. Most of the
metrics are just on that note, you were
on my show about a year and a half ago.
Yeah. You changed your mind over the
last year and a half. You you were kind
of leaning more towards recession then.
What changed your mind over the last
year?
Well, I don't think uh like I don't
think a recession's we should have had
14 recessions. We have had we we we were
rolling half of Biden's administration
was in a recession. No one's admitting
it. They don't they redefined they
redefined. So they have redefined GDP,
CPI, PPI. Yeah. Inflation is now has
another def. The VIX dude, you've been
watching the VIX forever. Okay. He and I
have been watching the V. When when
crude oil goes down $20 and the VIX
doesn't move or or you you say, "Oh
gosh, we just declared war against uh
Ukraine, nothing moves, man. And and the
VIX goes down and the S&P goes up."
you're like, "Hey, this is rigged. None
of these numbers make sense." And that
is why you get to Bitcoin so quick. It's
like, "Oh, wow. I'm actually I am most
certainly in a Ponzi scheme." To his
comment about, "Hey, half the people
here are dens." Half the people here are
some of the smartest people ever met in
my life. Yeah. There's no in between, I
guess. Some of them Some of them are
what you call the DJs. Yeah. Yeah.
Because they're learning through
exploratory. They're discovering stuff.
They're not all. Now, the other part of
this is there's a lot of a lot of
shitcoin talk out there. If you actually
go and meet some of these people, go
deep. The learning the learning from the
original say 12 years of people in
crypto. The learning, the study that is
achievable by just listening to the
mistakes these people made. This is the
book I would love to write or or
interview everybody that lost a billion
dollars
from crypto. The opportunity I I mean
Shimal Chamal should be sitting next to
the president of the United States right
now. He owned 5% of all the supply of
Bitcoin and sold it and then went did
did a bunch of spaxs. He would literally
be sitting with Sachs right now in the
office. And I I think that's a colossal
mistake. Wow. I own 5% of all the
Bitcoin and I sold it and now you see
what we see today. This thing is moving.
I mean, something is happening. Can we
go back to the liquidity question?
Because because because I think it's
really important because you you know I
I used to think I'm going to store
liquidity because I'm going to buy the
the bottom. I'm going to buy this place.
The truth is all I did was end up
watching money get depleted. and and so
I think uh since 2020 25 money's lost
25% of his value that that was that
mentality of I got to be liquid. So
right now what I do is every quarter I
try to dump out to zero. I try to find
someplace to go in because I've never
been able to time anything. This was
what gets me into this degenerate stuff
too by the way. Oh and most of these
people are buying at the top. They're
not buying at the bottom. They're buying
when the rush goes and all the news goes
positive and you look around you can't
see anything but you know bright lights
and all that glimmers is not gold you
know and and that's when a lot of people
are buying and that's why I don't that's
why Sailor and some of the great
investors talk about the dollar cost
averaging I'm going to buy it on the
15th regardless of the price put it away
and move on. Is that what you're doing?
That's what I'm doing.
And is that what you're doing? And then
I'm buying real estate constantly cuz I
thought I thought you didn't like some
of the prices. I mean I think I think
the sailors of the world the people that
really Well, I'm not I didn't buy any
today. If you mean if you mean that it's
today the 15th. Well, but I mean are you
buying 101
or I have bought I bought 108. I bought
106. I bought 105 strategies. But I've
also bought 75. Yeah. Right. Well,
you're both investors in Bitcoin now,
but you've got real estate portfolios.
You're adding hundred million to your $1
billion real estate fund. Who talked who
into who into buying Bitcoin? Who who
who's first? Well, I was born first.
Um, you know, we we we've had many many
discussions on the Bitcoin thing, you
know, trying I'm trying to understand
it. He's obviously spent a lot more time
learning about it. Um, and you know, I
think we were in a room one day and
somebody said in the room, we wanted
spaces and the guy's like, "Grant, you
should sell. you should get rid of your
$5 billion worth of real estate and have
it all in Bitcoin. And Gary popped up
and says, "Dude, you sound like an
idiot." Like, what are you talking
about? Are you going to dump your entire
business that you've built for 30 years
to be in this other asset class? And
that's what then I was in other rooms
where they're like, "Hey, what's better,
Bitcoin or stocks?" These debate rooms.
And then
he and I met we met sailor what back in
February, January, February this year
and just looked at how could how could I
mix the two together, you know? Uh I was
given some in 2013, bought some more in
16, bought some more in 20 um but not
big positions. Now I figured out how I
could do this on a regular basis where
my real estate's buying my Bitcoin. He
was given a 100red Bitcoin to speak for
one hour. Yeah. 10 mil. Yeah, not bad.
Let's I I think I had one shorten your
pizza with that people with their time.
But look, I think you know he he said
the the because it is a question a lot
of people go, "Hey, who was first in the
crypto? Who was first in real estate?"
He's been in real estate. I mean, he's
been in love with real estate since he
was a teenager. Um
he he made a comment earlier that how
conservative he is. And he is. I'm
really the opposite. Yeah. Okay. Like
I'm five years
And and it's not like I'll carry a lot
of losses, too. I mean, he's just never
gonna he will always look at me the
first two or three years of what I'm
doing going, "Bro, you're crazy. I mean,
I just like you're out of your mind." I
bet $25 on a blackjack table tonight.
That will not be his minimum bet. Oh, no
chance. Like, it just doesn't interest
me. But it but I lived in a world where
the numbers were larger and it was just
right. It doesn't like I'm not going to
do anyway. I think that explains the
difference. It's just a it's a mindset.
It's not really It's just a mindset of
what you're willing to look at and study
and learn.
Um I think it would be really cool for
people if they're looking for an
opportunity. I met somebody out there.
Hey, I'm lost. I don't know what to do.
I'm like, well, you're in the right
industry because nobody knows what we're
doing. So like nobody has an edge as
long as you're willing to come here.
Like there are real serious jobs to get
here. Now, this isn't just about
Bitcoin. Like, if you don't have a
dollar, you don't have to buy Bitcoin.
But come into this industry. It has
literally has open doors to everyone.
There's no closed doors. Uh that is a
phenomenal industry to be able to no
resume, no college education is
required. Buy onetenth of a Bitcoin and
join the club and and there's just so
many things to do, so many companies to
join.
Grant, you went on Undercover
Billionaire. Yeah. And you successfully
turned $100 to a company that's worth
$5.5 million in 90 days during co
without using my name, no social media,
no ads. Okay. So, for people that
haven't seen that episode, how did you
do it? Yeah. And if you were to do it
today, Yeah. if you would do it
differently.
Uh, no. I wouldn't do it differently,
but probably wouldn't do it at all. I
wouldn't do it at all. 100%. It was the
dumbest, most ridiculous, most painful
thing I've ever done in my entire life.
Um, look, the first thing I did, this
goes back to what I was saying to you
earlier about money. People do not need
cash. You know, I know he and I agree on
this. Like, if I was starting all over
again, I would be hustling people for
fiat. How do you do that? Uh, exchange
some value. Some value with you. Okay.
The value could be, "Hey, Bonnie, do you
have a $100 on you?" He used the word
hustle. He doesn't You haveundred on you
right now. Could you lend me $100? Sure.
Would you lend me a hundred? Yes. I
don't know when I can give it back to
you. Okay. What's the interest rate
you're charging him? Okay. I know. I
think it'd be nothing. I think it'd be
nothing. And I could run that hustle.
Okay. Now, obviously, I need to exchange
value with you or otherwise I'm not
going to be able to repeat that with you
because then that's just a bad hustle.
But then I'm going to take that $100.
What I did on Undercover Billionaire
that that caused Discovery Channel and
me to be angry at each other all the
time is they wanted me to they wanted me
to spend the money.
And I said, "No, no, I'm dropping the
money off at the bank." And they said,
"Why we we need to see it go from 100 to
82 to 64 to That's TV show." I said,
"This isn't a produced TV show. You guys
are going to follow me. I'mma turn $100
into 10 million bucks in 90 days.
For me to do that, I need to drop off
this hundred at the bank and go to zero
right now. I'm not going to have money.
I never bought anything the entire 90
days. I never spent a penny.
Everybody else funded every activity I
did. And so, um, we built a marketing
company in in Pueblo, Colorado. And and,
uh, it worked good. I'd probably do it
again like if I wanted to make a bunch
of money. Everybody's got marketing
problems. Bitcoin does not solve every
problem in the universe. I know the
Bitcoiners out there, they they're all
like, "This is going to solve the water
problems and the wars. There's not going
to be more wars. Nobody will be hungry."
Yeah. Yeah. That's not true. Okay. You
got human beings causing those problems.
Now, money does not cause those
problems. It funds a lot of the
dumbness. But, uh, so I would do that
that again. I would I I had no money
every night. I got somebody to provide
me with a place to sleep. So, if we if
we just think about what you just said
because I this is where we disagree,
right? I think money is actually the the
way money has been uh populated across
the planet is one of the core issues and
this is what turns people into animals
and and constantly having to run harder
cut corners because the gravity of the
universe around them whether it's the
cost of eggs the cost of milk the cost
of gasoline the cost of housing which by
the way I think housing is the only
thing that's inflated Everything else
has been sh supply shock inflation where
prices go. That is not real inflation.
Okay, that is blow up a pipeline and the
energy prices to Germany go up triple.
Well, that that that's intervention.
Okay, we intervene all the time. I think
we would have far less wars. If you
studied Bitcoin more and you studied how
money is being adulterated, I think
that's the right word or bastardized. It
is creating real behavioral issues like
people are cheating and stealing and
doing things that they only do under
duress. I think most people are good
people but when they get scared and and
they see no possible way to win. They do
things that are bad. And I think money
is really we've added 40% of all the
paper in the United States was added in
the last five years. It's a lot of
money. Gary, let me let me ask you and
then maybe Grant can chime in. You
probably get asked this every day,
Bitcoin or real estate now that you're
invested. But let me give you a personal
anecdote, right? Because we you and I
talked about this on Twitter a lot. I
bought my first condo, my home, when I
was 24. The amount of money I put in on
that property, if I had held that in
Bitcoin and not sold today, it'd be
worth over 60 million. Yeah. And I
sometimes lose sleep over that. But the
upside is I had a place to live. I had a
roof over my head. stability so I can't
look back with regret and of course I
have made some that sorry could have
rented could have rent yeah exactly
um I mean I didn't have 2020 vision back
then I didn't know Bitcoin was going to
go to $110,000
so how do you evaluate that today
someone comes to you hey I've got a I
got 300 grand I need to buy something
need to rent
okay renting or buying versus the
American dream let's let's but yeah but
that question first and then we'll we'll
address that. Look, I I I I think uh
I'll just cut to the chase. Owning a
home is a horrible horrible horrible
investment. Interesting. Okay. Horrible.
It it Look, let's pretend like you get
married to to Lenny. You guys are like
y'all love each other. It's awesome. And
then, hey, you got to buy a house.
Because that's what her mom and her mom
and her mom and her mom said. That's
success. And by the way, that's an
investment. Which by the way, I don't
know when that happened, when it became
an investment, but nonetheless, it's
investment. It never ever gets retraded
by the wife. The triple the house could
triple. You never hear the wife going,
"Let's sell it and make our 300%." That
never It's not an investment, by the
way. It's not liquid. It anchors you
down. This 4% arbitrage rate that
flipped up to eight. This another trap.
people. Oh, I'm going to stay here in
Oklahoma where there's no jobs cuz I
have a 4% mortgage on a $700,000 house
and I don't want to pay an extra 300
basis points for my life to live in a
great city for three%. That's
ridiculous. That tells me people do not
understand about core decisions just on
math and education and blowing through.
How do you beat inflation and gravity?
And so it's a horrible I think Bitcoin
is the greatest investment
uh risk adjusted and energy adjusted
meaning how much energy does Gary
Cardone have to put into it? I never get
called by my girlfriend to go, "Hey, go
up on the Bitcoin roof and clean the
leaves." I never get that phone call.
Okay? I never, hey, hurricane incoming
to Bitcoin. Okay? By the way, the
plumbing's broken down here while I'm
doing this interview and I have to stop
the interview because my pl I become a
plumber. By the way, I'm a bad plumber.
Okay, these are things that I want to
rent. I want to rent a plumber. I want
to rent the fire guy. I want to rent the
house. Just to play devil's advocate,
but you could buy that property, rent it
out, get someone to manage and do all
that crap for you. Be an awful awful
investment though because better for me
to buy Bitcoin and never get a
maintenance call. I never get a tax
call. I never get a insurance call. I
never get anything. It goes up only 15%
a year. Let's just assume 12 or 15% a
year. It's unbelievable for energy for
the amount of energy I put in, right?
And I can rent. I have rented most of
the homes in my entire life. My children
have spent 17 houses my ch children have
lived in. They don't know if it's rented
or not. They don't care. It's the pillow
is the pillow. I've never had someone
come to a party go, "By the way, knockk
knockock. Do you own this? Did anybody
buy this hotel so you could come stay
here for two nights?" No. Nobody cares.
Why are we ashamed of renting? It's a
bizarre thing. Grant, back to your
point. Somebody who's thinking of buying
another property soon, talk me out of
it. Well, it doesn't make money. I mean,
it's it's adjusted for inflation. It's
like 1% a year for the last 100 years.
It generates no energy, man. Okay. It's
it's a liability. should not even be
called. It should be illegal to say a
home is an investment. It should be
illegal to not have
uh some kind of full transparency
disclosure that saving is an oxymoron.
You cannot save money.
You know, the fact that the fact that
people think they're saving money is it
should be this money cannot be saved. In
fact, if you look at the K shiller home
price index, it's only been going up
since the beginning of history. 57 times
in my lifetime. Yeah, it's gone up 57
times in my lifetime, but that doesn't
include the insurance I paid. Sure. The
taxes I paid, the HOA fees I paid, the
maintenance I paid, the three roofs I
bought, the m blah blah blah. And I was
stuck in one location. And what else
could I have done with that money? So,
what I would I would agree with you on
this. I would go buy a 25 rentals,
not one place in rent, because then
you're dependent upon one tenant. So,
you really work for them now because you
got to be sure they stay there. I'd have
25 or 30 rentals paying me cash flow and
get the cash flow and buy my Bitcoin.
Like we would we would never even
consider buying one place and renting it
out. Yeah. Because you lose that one
guy, you're done. You're 100% vacant.
You're done. And this it just makes no
sense. It's a liability again. Look, I
own a house that I bought. That's why
Can I just finish one other thing? Like
the best some of the best debt in this
country is still available even though
we complain about it at 5 and a half%.
It's still some of the best debt because
on 300 units or 456 units that cash
flows $6 million in net profit, I'm
going to get the best mortgage. I think
in the future, you're going to put what
we're doing with real estate and
Bitcoin. You're going to put those two
together as a hybrid where it ends up
being 50% $100 million real estate, $100
million of Bitcoin, and you're going to
get a you're going to get a $120 million
loan on that hybrid long-term 20-year
mortgage. Caner down the down the whale
will put together a mortgage product.
Fanny and Freddy will end up with Bit
Bitcoin Bitcoin hybrid. You don't like
my guys at Caner. No, bro. That hook got
set so hard on you though, dude. Those
are my friends down there. Just keep
talking. Those are my friends down
there. Baby. Well, those are my friends
down there. You're doing good, dude. So,
so um
anyway, I think some of those So,
because the mortgage products are a
problem, too. Like when you want to get
out of your mortgage, it's hard to undo
it. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. You can also use
that money to buy a private jet. You
did? Yes. Um, and before the jet company
even told you they had a jet, you wired
the full mount. You done You've done
some good research. I watch your videos,
man. And I want to know what gave you
the confidence. You're like, I believe
I'll get this jet. Yeah. This was what
year was that, Ryan, that we bought the
550?
Yeah. So, I needed this tax breaks. It
was December. I think it was the 12th of
the month.
I couldn't find another way. I I had a
plane. I had a GFream 200
and had it sold. Called Gulfream and
said, "I need a plane." Because my tax
attorney, my tax guy said, "There's no
write offs. There's nothing else you can
do." And I owed like 50 million bucks. I
said, "There's always something you can
do about it. I could give it away. I
could buy equipment. I could, you know,
go buy another piece of real estate. I
could buy a jet." So, I called Gulf
Stream. said, "I need a 550 before the
end of the year. We don't have one." Um,
I short sto to shorten the story, I sent
him a wire after he told me no three
times. I sent him a wire for $55
million.
Called him back. I said, "Hey, can you
find me a plane?" He's like, "Grant, I
just told you, man." I said, "Check with
your accounting department. You're going
to see a wire just hit." Okay. Yeah. He
called me back. He's like, "Bro,
nobody's ever done that. That is the
most gangster
freaking move I've ever seen in my
life." I said, 'You want to send me that
55 million back or you want to find me a
plane? And he found me a plane.
Wow. You know how hard it would be for a
company to send $55 million back? Could
have done that in Bitcoin today. I would
have got tax write off. Yeah, that's
another thing. Bitcoin doesn't do
everything. Like I come to this
conference like Bitcoin does everything.
Yeah. Can't get a tax write off. Yeah.
It does not cash flow. Even though I
hear people talk about my Bitcoin yields
46% a year. I'm like where's the yield?
The y a yield is money coming in not I
don't know how they figure out this
yield thing how they even get away with
saying it but so I get great tax write
offs I get the appreciation of the real
estate as you guys print more money as
we print more money real estate values
are going to continue to go up that's
the only thing that drove up those 57x
you think they keep printing of course
they're going to keep printing how can
we play the game if they don't keep
printing even in monopoly it's allowed
to bring more paper into the game
printing producing in credit. What does
that do to Bitcoin? It becomes more
valuable. Yeah. What would what happens
to real estate? What do you think? What
happens to the price of everything?
Well, let me ask you this. Let me answer
one question. What would happen to real
estate if you couldn't borrow 80 cents
on the dollar? It would go down in
value. How much? It would go down
probably 40%.
So what would happen to Bitcoin if you
could borrow any which means a guy like
me that can pay cash would steal real
estate that what would happen to Bitcoin
if you could actually do the same thing
and borrow 80 cents on the dollar.
By the way, I'm not suggesting that you
can do that. But what would happen?
Because that would put bit that would
put real estate and Bitcoin on an equal
playing field and you don't have that.
Not you don't have a use you don't have
a use. You don't have What would happen
to car? Nobody's sleeping in Bitcoin,
bro. Like like you guys got to get off
this craziness. This is about investing.
Can you sleep in a Bitcoin? I don't
think so. We already decided that you
can rent. It's not sheltered though. You
can rent. But this is where it gets
crazy. The conversation gets nuts though
right now because you're going to
compare one asset that's worth $2
trillion to every asset on the planet.
It's like there's not going to be any
other assets. And this is ridiculous.
You know, there's going to be other
assets. I think but I I don't look I
think you're conflating like I I don't
hear people saying it's going to solve
everything but you're not answering the
question what would happen to Bitcoin if
you could borrow 80 cents on the dollar.
I think a bunch of people going to have
their Bitcoin stolen from them from from
the lender. Okay, that that's a really
bizarre answer but like that's what I
think I think the point Okay, so I think
a bunch of those 50% of those out there
are going to lose their Bitcoin
position. Well, the DGM by themsel they
don't actually own the Bitcoin. they
somebody else they they're they're
playing in a different field. But if
real estate prices would get cut by 40%
if you couldn't borrow 80 cents on the
dollar. Yeah. I think that says a lot.
That means that home prices would come
down to 175,000 as an average grant.
That won't happen to single family
homes. You have a 30-year mortgage.
There's nothing to do that. You got 27
years before that expires. So, you're
saying the trap in real estate that's
set for most
uh investors is we're going to loan you
so much money that you're going to buy
into a trap that you'll never be able to
every 10 to 12 years there's a real
estate real estate correction in this
country has happened for the last
hundreds of years and it always happens
because of the debt debt crisis. Always
has nothing to do with the real estate.
It was the debt tied to the real estate.
So if you tie 80% of the debt to the
Bitcoin, you will have that traded every
seven or eight years when the banks
decide to pull the rug,
it's the same problem. So if you don't
like liquidity and you don't like cash,
why is it? Because I look at Bitcoin as
the ultimate investment, it's not a
savings program. And as long as my as
long as my cash burn, the amount of
money I have to spend every day is not
over what my Bitcoin holdings are, I
don't need distributions from anything.
I don't need any more. In fact, I don't
want any more income. I would like a
greater investment. And to me, housing,
stocks, bonds, Bitcoin, I can make an
investment for the next eight years in a
Bitcoin that also like structurally sits
really well with real estate. Fouryear
investment versus 10year, stack those
together. Look, I don't think there's
any right or wrong. I But I'm not going
to make little of anybody doing 100%
Bitcoin or 40% real estate or I don't
think there's any right or wrong.
Everyone's different. But to be zero of
Bitcoin, I think that's a big mistake. I
got one more question, then I'll pass
with Bonnie to finish. What is your
biggest business mistake, failure that
you've learned from?
Man, mine mine has been not taking
enough risk. Okay.
100%. Like I have Yeah. But you're
saying that in hindsight. Yeah. Well,
you took just as much risk as you needed
to at the time, right? Could you say
that? No, he's he's answering. I mean,
he's he's saying I should have taken
more. I should be worth 10 or 15 times
what I'm worth. Yeah. I just I avoided.
I worked. I saved.
I saved. I worked. And then
real estate was the first thing I could
make big bets on that I felt like, okay,
I'm not going to lose here. And now I
can add to that like bit real my
brother's I mean real estate is very
slow and boring and it's heavy and you
can't lift it and
you know when we add the Bitcoin to it
though it's going to lighten the load.
It's going to give it's going to give
one of the most stable proven investment
classes on planet earth this last 2,000
years or longer. People seek shelter.
They're going to pay for it or they're
going to pay for it. One of the two. And
um and the Bitcoin gives it a big lift.
gives a really something with no
liquidity. Liquidity, no volatility with
volatility could be a great thing. Gary,
dude, I've made so many mistakes. You
You live You do business the way I I'
I've lost so much money. Um,
do I call those mistakes? I'm not sure I
call them mistakes. If I learned
something from Dude, it's not a mistake.
I just had to go through it. The
greatest mistake though has been like he
and I don't do any business together and
we don't do it because like one there
cannot possibly be two captains on the
ship. I mean we're just going to run it
right on the rocks. But doing business
with a family member that has been a
tragic tragic I mean a quarter of a
billion dollar mistake. That's a monster
mistake. What doing doing business going
into business with you know I got
married to somebody being not me. I want
to clear this up. It's got nothing to do
with I wanted to clear up that we don't
I've made him nothing but money. So, um
and uh so that that's that's been a huge
That wasn't a family member. That was
It's a time suck though. I lost a lot of
time. Um and quite frankly, um I've
always been able to pivot really, really
fast.
There were businesses there that I was
like, "Oh man, we need to convert the
whole thing to crypto." I mean, I knew
this was happening and I'm stuck. I was
literally stuck in a business. So, here
I was stuck in an operating business
that I couldn't get out of knowing full
well, my god, man. I mean, my partner
called up our investment banker once in
2019.
He bought $8 million worth of Bitcoin.
And the guy, best investment guy in the
world in in the fintech space, he said
he's a god. Did he really? When was
this? Was calling. What year was this?
19 or something. He's like, "Dude,
seriously, he did that? Oh my god." So,
uh, it's just getting in bed with the
wrong partners. Yeah. That dude kills.
I've had a couple bad partners. Oh, it's
But you don't know. You know, they
started off good. Everybody believes in
the partnership in the beginning.
If you could go back to when Gary was 20
years old and now you meet this
20-year-old Gary, what would you say to
him? Except for buy Bitcoin later, but
what would you say to him? Well, well, I
wouldn't say buy Bitcoin. That would not
that would not be the piece of advice.
When you're 20 years old, where were you
when you were 20? You're in college.
Yeah. You're going to college,
man. Look, if I'm if I'm I have more
wisdom now. I'm You're Yeah. Yeah. Who
you are now, knowing everything that you
know. I probably wouldn't give him any
advice cuz I know he's not going to
listen to me anyways and be like, "Fuck
you, man." And I don't think he's going
to listen to me.
Um I mean, there's only one piece of
advice he can give me when I'm 20. Dude,
get off of drugs. I was on drugs every
day. So, there's only one That was
probably the biggest mistake of my life
was 10 years drugs. I I think I would
tell him uh hey f fine. Like
look, I really what I should have said
about him earlier when you asked me to
define him was I couldn't come up with
anything that he was a powerhouse. Uh
that that I think he found his passion
and he just went into it and whether it
was a loan or like we were really single
focused people. We're not like he and I
barely have any investments. People are
st we have no advisors. I've never had a
financial adviser in my life. I wouldn't
listen to somebody about what to do with
my money for the I I I don't listen to
him like I'm going to do my own deal and
but if he's passionate I would tell
anybody to just blow yourself into
something is so exciting. It's almost as
exciting as sex. Just get into something
that you love. And I I use that because
it's it should be passionate and
exciting. And when it's not, work
through the boredom or get out. If
you're bored of like I've been in four,
it definitely needs to last longer than
it sex. I literally can shortterm six or
eight years that I if I stay in the
industry, I am going to become stale and
my value will go down because I'm no
longer interested uh in learning
anything. And that's I'm excited for him
because he's coming into the space. He's
going to fight it. You see, you can see
the ego. No, no, no. Real estate's good.
Bitcoin's better. And it's just gonna be
gonna be I've not I don't even know why
you talk about that to me. It's not even
a you're you're you're you're just
twitching a little bit. We see the
legacy twitches from you from the
background. I mean, it's just, you know,
but we love you, man. I think I think
you know what what I'm doing with this
real estate space. Like, it's like it's
not going away. People have to have a
place to live. Yeah. There is $350
trillion worth of real estate on planet
Earth. is probably the largest asset
class on the planet combined. Yeah.
Right. It is. It's massive. You're not
getting rid of that ever. Never. Nothing
disrupts. Do you think that continues to
grow? And can that bubble get bigger?
Because you made a comment about hey for
Bitcoin. It's going to it's going to get
bigger. It's going to get bigger through
natural inflation. Everybody should wish
for inflation. Everybody should want
inflation. Inflation is a great great
thing. If you own too much of it, hey,
well, I mean, I don't know what too much
is as long as I own the right assets.
Yeah. you know, then I want it.
Hey guys, that was great. Yeah, that was
an amazing talk. I'm I'm happy with you
guys just showing up, but hey, if you're
happy, you guys happy at hello. That was
that was amazing.